Curriculum Vitae of MD. MEHEDI HASAN



Career Objective:

I am a progressive professional worker in the development sector with over 3 years of proven experience scholarly engaged with various projects in several organizations. In addition, I am holding a master's degree in Social Science with special concentration on Project Cycle Management, Public Policy Analysis, and Research Methodology. I am currently seeking **project management** related jobs that will allow me to take challenges and apply my analytical, technical, capacity building, team building, and communications skill.

Education:

2012-2013 : Master of Social Sciences (**M.S.S.**), Public Administration, University of Dhaka. : Bachelor of Social Sciences (**B.S.S.**), Public Administration, University of Dhaka.

Professional Experiences:

February 01, 2018 to Present

Position held : Officer (Project Support & Coordination)

Major Projects - Baseline survey of EMP preparation of Matarbari USCCF Power Plant Project

Dhaka - CTG - Cox's Bazaar Railway ProjectDhaka - Joydevpur - Ishwardy Railway Project

- Environmental Master Plan Project (All over Bangladesh)

Organization : Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd.

- To manage administrative, development, planning, and implementation policies,

procedures and programs in support of the project;

- Expedite project implementation by maintaining liaison with government/non-

government authority, local & international agencies and other stakeholders;
Review and check documents related with bid, contract and any other request

Succinct responsibilities - Review and check documents related with bid, cont received from project implementing agencies;

- Support to prepare presentation, event report, organizing meeting/seminar, internal

events, programs & field visit as and when necessary;

- Perform any other duties as may be assigned by the authority.

January 01, 2017 to January 31, 2018

Position held : Field Investigator

Major Projects - Baseline survey of EMP preparation of Matarbari USCCF Power Plant Project

- Third Urban Governance & Infrastructure Improvement Project (UGIIP-3)

- Environmental Master Plan Project (All over Bangladesh)

- Drainage Master Plan Project (16 Districts)

Organization : Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd.

- Collaborating with customers, claimants, policyholders & the local administration;

- Field visit as and when necessary;

- Organize and facilitate focus group discussion;

Succinct responsibilities - Support in conducting EMP, social/baseline surveys as and when required;

- Assist in data collection, report preparation and further tasks as per instruction by the authorized management;

- Draft accurate and concise reports & presentations based on all collected findings.

March 01, 2016 to September 30, 2016

Position held : Research Associate

Organization : Human Development Research Centre (HDRC)

Distinctive Attributes:

- Profound knowledge on MS Word, MS Excel, PowerPoint, Web Applications, Social Media, HTML, CSS, Oracle/My SQL, Java etc.
- Typing Bangla with Bijoy software
- Flexible to travel frequently
- Team Building Skills

- Ability to work under pressure
- Report writing skills
- Adaptability with changes
- Well-disciplined, Self-motivated & Goal-oriented
- Communication & Liaison skills

Other Experiences & Voluntary Activities:

- Worked as a **Research Associate** (Part Time) of **Center for Asia-Pacific Initiative** (**CAPI**) for the period of 05.04.2019 to 05.08.2019 on the **Piloting Phase** of SME base Comparative Study in Developing Country
- Worked as a **Coordinator** in the Social Action Project "ইচ্ছেপূরণ (Icchepuron)" under the **Active Citizens Youth Leadership Training program** of British Council, supported by **Democracywatch**. http://www.dwatch-bd.org/ylp1.html
- Conduct several field researches on Contemporary Local Government in Bangladesh, Politicization of Professionals, Migration Pattern in Dhaka city, and Corruption & Tadbir in Bureaucracy.
- Involved in organizing the festival entitled, "Bijoy-e Parbon-e" arranged by Utshe, marking 41st Victory Day of Bangladesh. http://www.thedailystar.net/news-detail-261174
- Founder member of the voluntary group "Friends Society of Rangpur" http://fsrbd.org/
- Voluntary regular **Blood Donor** (26th times till now).

Training and Workshop:

- Trainee (completed) of "IDB-BISEW IT Scholarship Project, Round-39" in "Enterprise Systems Analysis & Design-J2EE". http://idb-bisew.org/
- Participant of the Active Citizens Youth Leadership Training Programme of British Council, supported by Democracywatch. https://www.britishcouncil.org/active-citizens
- Attended the Climate Culture and Art Symposium 2018 for Youth in Bangladesh under the Gobeshona Young Researcher's programme organized by ICCCAD. http://art-symposium-4youth.icccad.net/
- A Six (6) months training experience on Social Compliance and CSR Issues, organized by Institute of Apparel Research and Technology, (**BKMEA**). http://www.bkmea.com/training_institite.html

Personal Information:

Address : Central Road First Drive, House – 111, Flat – 5B, Kolabagan, Dhaka-1205.

Contact No : +880-1717-677451, +880-1918-629865

E-mail : mhshuvo29@gmail.com
Nationality : Bangladeshi by Birth

Languages : Advanced Bangla, Fluent English and some understanding of Hindi.

Passport No : BM0481157 Blood group : O Positive

Distinction:

2005 : Got a board scholarship for achieving Golden A⁺.

References:

Abu Jubayer, Director (Operation), Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd. and Deputy

Referee 1 Director (Operation), CCECR, Stamford University Bangladesh, Dhaka.

Cell: +880-1711459532 Email: jubayer.buet.bd@gmail.com

Md. Sultan Mahmud, Senior Sector Specialist (CEP, GJ&D and HRLS),

Referee 2 IDP, BRAC, Baniachong, Habigonj.

Cell: +880-1730-347653 Email: sultan.mahmud@brac.net

Acknowledgement:

I, the undersigned hereby certify that, to the best of my knowledge and belief, above mentioned credentials correctly describe myself, and I will be liable for any feigned information.

Md. Mehedi Hasan